Tim Carlock



timothy.carlock@gmail.com



314.719.9051



New York, NY



http://timcarlock.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tscarlock/



https://github.com/tcarlock

I have over 15 years of engineering and product-development experience, with a particular interest in organizational design, product strategy and user experience. I have sector experience in financial services, consumer tech and business software. I cofounded a software startup where I managed product strategy and development, and I was an early(ish) employee at Uber.

Experience

Senior Engineering Manager - Customer Service Experience | Better.com | New York, NY

Nov 2020 - Jun 2020

- Led an organization of approximately 30 engineers and 3 engineering managers who were collectively responsible for the customer-service experience throughout the loan application and closing process. After a reorganization and rechartering effort, this included four teams focused on comms tooling (telephony, SMS and email), comms compliance/reporting, issue resolution and top-of-funnel conversion.
- Supported and coached three engineering managers including one who was in his first year as a manager. Key areas of focus included forming team culture, establishing and improving process, mentoring and developing engineers, and managing PM partnerships.
- · Worked with recruiting to identify areas of improvement in the Engineer-interviewing process, and laid out a strategy for overhauling key elements of the framework. Primarily, this included articulating a hiring philosophy, improving definition and training for the module-owner and bar-raiser programs and implementing a pair-programming module.
- Designed and implemented a checkpoint framework for planning, developing and launching long-running, crossorganizational initiatives. This provided functional teams with greater visibility and foresight and increased alignment for teams working on dependent tasks/projects, and it became the basis for the org-wide program-management framework implemented by Product Operations.

Engineering Manager - Eats (Restaurant Acquisition) | Uber | New York, NY

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Leading a product-engineering group consisting of 16 engineers and one engineering manager split across three subteams: accounts platform, sales insights and self-signup (https://www.ubereats.com/restaurant/signup).
- · Re-organized the engineering and product teams to increase development velocity, simplify project staffing and create new growth and development opportunities for engineers. Along with the Product Manager, I co-developed the team's revised vision, strategy, OKRs/KPIs and roadmap.
- Established structure and processes for the team's projects, including a sprint-inspired process and pod-based approach to project staffing.
- Onboarded 11 engineers in the Toronto office and established an interim 6-month roadmap while their product organization was being built out.

Engineering Manager - Core Infra (Developer Experience) | Uber | San Francisco, CA

March 2017 - Jan 2019

- Managed 11 engineers and tech leads across two sub-teams responsible for a portfolio of developer tools and automatedtesting services.
- Worked with Product and Design to maintain a product roadmap, prioritize and plan projects and support an internal user base of 2,600 spread across 90 teams.
- Managed systems and initiatives to streamline manual testing and introduce an organization-wide platform for automated mobile and back-end testing.

Senior Engineer & Team Lead - Shared Rides | Uber | San Francisco, CA

May 2016 - March 2017

- Technical leader for a team responsible for a variety of internal tools used to streamline and administer the Uber Pool
 product including mapping/pickup region management, test-trip automation, pricing experimentation and trip visualization.
- Formed and lead an internal community of web engineers focused on professional development and standards setting.

Senior Engineer & Team Lead - Uber for Business | Uber | San Francisco, CA

May 2014 - May 2016

- I led the team responsible for building and maintaining the business-facing dashboard of the U4B product.
- Worked closely with Product and Design and managed the prioritization, planning and implementation of a variety of key
 features including employee management, ride policies and billing.
- Led the effort to migrate the client application from BackboneJS to React and Redux.

Senior Engineer | Learnist | San Francisco, CA

Feb 2013 - May 2014

- I was a full-stack engineer and worked with Ruby on Rails and AngularJS, as well other technologies including CSS3, Sass,
 CoffeeScript, Redis and Rspec.
- Rebuilt the email-preference-management system including a redesign of the data-storage architecture, authorization and the UI for preference management.
- Rebuilt the content-curation UI and workflow, and created new designs for the primary application views.
- Managed a full migration from server-rendered views to a single page app built on AngularJS.

Software Engineer II | Expedia | San Francisco, CA

May 2012 - Feb 2013

- Developed an API to serve localized hotel reviews for multiple Expedia properties including search and travel packages. The API was developed using Java/Spring and MongoDB and was deployed to EC2.
- Managed deployment and provisioning using Jenkins, Capistrano and Chef.

Co-Founder & Product Lead / Nexly / San Francisco, CA

Aug 2009 - April 2012

Nexly was a lead-generation and tracking toolset for business-services companies. I was responsible for product strategy and development.

- Worked closely with users to understand key problems and needs, identify features and develop a product roadmap.
- Hired and managed designers and developers and oversaw all aspects of feature development and deployment.
- Developed the application using Rails and PostgreSQL running on Heroku. Front-end technologies included CSS3, jQuery, Sass and HAML.

Education

University of Missouri - St Louis | Bachelor of Science - Information Systems

Aug 2004

Coursework in system architecture, relational databases, OOP and language design and project management.

University of Missouri - St Louis | Bachelor of Science - Finance

Jan 2003

Coursework in asset pricing, asset allocation and portfolio management, corporate finance, economic modeling and accounting.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, Java, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS/Sass

Frameworks/Libraries: React/ReactNative, Redux, Ruby on Rails

Tools: Confluence, Jira, Phabricator, Git, Jenkins, Figma, Sketch